American Psychological Association Records
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Administration, 1918-1985 (Box 29-292)
  - Executive Officers File, 1918-1978 (Box 29-132)
    - Executive secretary (Box 29)
      - Willard Clifford Olson
        - American Journal of Psychology, 1940-1941
          - National Council of Women Psychologists, 1942-1944
          - National Council on Rehabilitation, 1943-1946 (Box 40)
          - National Defense Research Commission, Applied Psychology Panel, 1942-1945
          - National Institute of Mental Health, 1945
          - National Institute of Psychology, 1938-1942
          - National Mental Health Act, 1945-1952
          - National Occupational Conference, 1937-1939
          - National Research Council
            - Committee on Food Habits, 1941-1943
            - General, 1938-1946, (3 folders)
            - Miscellany, 1942-1946 (Box 41)
          - National Roster of Scientific and Specialized Personnel, 1940-1943
          - National Wartime Conference, 1944
          - Necrology, 1937-1945, (4 folders)
          - New York Management Council, 1937-1941
          - New York State Association of Applied Psychologists, 1937-1945
          - Nonpayment of dues, 1945
          - Occupational requests and information, 1937-1945, (2 folders)
          - Office of Defense Transportation, 1944-1945
          - Office of Psychological Personnel
            - Jan.-June 1942
            - July 1942-Nov. 45, (3 folders) (Box 42)
          - Office of Scientific Personnel, 1942-1951
          - Office of Scientific Research and Development, 1946-1951
          - Ohio Association for Applied Psychology, 1941-1944
          - Paterson, Donald Gildersleeve, 1934-1938
          - Pennsylvania Association of Clinical Psychologists, 1938-1944
          - Picture project, 1954-1955
          - Placement requests, 1937-1942
          - Policies for transitional year, ballots, 1944
          - Policy and Planning Board, 1945
          - Post-council members and National Research Council representatives, 1940
          - Presidential correspondence, 1938-1945, (2 folders)
          - Presidents of the APA, undated
          - Press relations, suggestions for the future, 1941
          - Program Committee
            - Correspondence
              - Nov. 1937-Dec. 1940
              - Jan. 1941-June 1945, (4 folders) (Box 43)
          - Psi Chi, 1940-1944
          - Psychological Abstracts, 1934-1945
          - Psychological Bulletin, 1938-1945
          - Psychological Corporation, 1943-1945
          - Psychological Monographs, 1942
          - Psychological Review, 1937-1944
          - Psychologists' League, 1936-1944 (Box 44)
          - Psychology Newsletter, 1942-1945, (2 folders)
          - Psychometric Society, 1937-1945
          - Publications of the APA, special rates for service people, 1944
          - Publicity Committee,1940-1941
          - Recruitment of old members, 1932-1945
          - Regional representatives, 1945
          - Resignations for yearbooks
            - 1943
            - 1944-1946, (3 folders) (Box 45)
          - Rocky Mountain branch of APA, 1937-1945
          - Rorschach Institute, 1940
          - Science Service, 1938-1942
          - Security plans for employees, 1938-1939
          - Social Science Research Council, 1937-1945
          - Society for the Psychological Study of Broadcasting, 1943
          - Society of Experimental Psychologists, 1943-1944
          - South American relations, 1940-1941
          - Southern Society for Philosophy and Psychology, 1936-1944
          - Southwestern Psychological Association, 1942-1945
          - Statistics and statistical charts, 1920
          - Stoelting Co., proposed purchase, 1943
          - Treasurer, nominations, 1935-1936
          - Unesco, 1945
          - Valentine, Willard L., 1942-1945 (Box 46)
          - War cases, 1941-1945
          - Washington-Baltimore branch of APA, 1937-1945
          - Watson, Goodwin, 1942-1943
          - Western Psychological Association, 1937-1945
          - Wisconsin Association for Applied Psychology, 1940-1944
          - Yearbook payments due, 1944-1945
          - Yerkes Committee
            - Miscellaneous reports, 1944-1945
            - Psychological warfare, 1944-1945
            - Record of material received, 1945
      - Dael Lee Wolfle
        - General correspondence
          - A, 1946-1950, (1 folder)
          - B-F, 1946-1950, (5 folders) (Box 47)
          - G-N, 1946-1950, (7 folders) (Box 48)
          - O-Z, 1946-1950, (7 folders) (Box 49)
        - Related officers (Box 50)
          - President, 1945-1950, (2 folders)
          - Recording secretary, 1945-1950, (5 folders)
          - Treasurer, 1944-1950
        - Convention Program Committee, general correspondence, 1946-1949, (3 folders) (Box 51)
        - Government agencies file
          - Bureau of the Budget, 1946
          - Civil Service Commission, 1947, undated
          - Department of Commerce, undated
          - Department of State, 1947-1948
          - Department of the Air Force
            - Aero Medical Laboratory, 1946-1947
            - Rand Corp., 1949
            - Research and development, 1948
          - Department of the Army
            - Adjutant General's Office, 1947-1950
            - Armed Forces Institute, 1950 (Box 52)
            - General staff, 1946-1949
          - Department of the Navy
            - Familiarization Course in Psychology
              - Correspondence, 1948
              - Lectures, 1948
            - Office of Naval Research
              - Contracts, 1948-1950
              - Correspondence and miscellany, 1947-1950
              - Human Relations Advisory Panel, 1946-1950
              - Research Proposals, 1947-1950, (3 folders) (Box 53)
          - Federal Security Agency
            - Children's Bureau, 1949-1950
            - Office of Education, 1946-1949
          - National Institute of Mental Health, 1946-1950, (2 folders)
          - Office of the Surgeon General, 1946-1949
          - Post Office Department, 1946
          - Selective Service Commission, 1948
          - Veterans Administration
            - Clinical Psychology Section, 1946-1948
            - Miscellany, 1946, 1953 (Box 54)
            - Vocational Rehabilitation, 1944-1946
        - Organizations
          - National Advisory Mental Health Council, 1947
          - National Association for Mental Health, requests regarding clinical psychology, 1950
          - National Defense Research Commission, draft, applied psychology panel history, 1946
          - National Research Council
            - Committee on Asian Anthropology, 1947
            - Committee on International Exchange of Persons, 1949-1950
            - Committee on Undersea Warfare, 1950-1951
            - Committee on United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization, 1947-1950
            - Correspondence, 1946-1950
            - Office of Scientific Personnel, 1946-1950 (Box 55)
            - Psi Chi, 1949
            - Reports and miscellany, 1946-1950
            - Studies for international science, 1949
          - National Society for Medical Research, 1946
          - Office of Scientific Personnel, 1946-1950
          - Office of Scientific Research and Development, 1946-1948, (2 folders)
          - Research and Development Board
            - Committee on Human Resources, 1947-1950
            - Panel on scientific and specialized personnel, 1948-1950 (Box 56)
            - Reports and miscellany, 1946, 1950-1951
        - Representatives
          - Advisory Council on Human Relations, 1946-1948
          - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1946-1948
          - American Documentation Institute, 1946-1950
          - American Standards Association, 1947
          - Groupement Internationale Pour la Coordination dela Psychiatrie, 1950
          - International Society of Color Council, 1946-1949
          - National Council on Rehabilitation, 1946-1949 (Box 57)
          - Social Science Research Council
            - Committee on Government Research, 1946-1948
            - Committee on War Studies, 1946-1949
            - Correspondence, reports, and miscellany, 1946-1950
          - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization, 1946-1950
          - World Federation for Mental Health, 1948-1950, (2 folders)
        - Subject file (Box 58)
          - Accounts and finances
            - American Security and Trust Co., 1947-1949
            - Taxes, 1949
          - Administrative manual, undated
          - Armed Forces Familiarization Course in Military Psychology
            - Booklet, 1949
            - Correspondence, 1949
            - Lectures, 1949, (3 folders)
            - Miscellany, 1949-1950
          - Army Advisory Committee on Psychological Programs, 1948-1949
          - Board of Directors, loyalty investigations, 1949-1950
          - Committee on Surplus War Materials, 1946 (Box 59)
          - Committee on Training, 1948-1950
          - Council of Editors, 1949-1951
          - Harvard Commission, 1947-1948
          - Library, archives, and museum collection, undated
          - Mail records, 1947
          - National Mental Health Act, 1946
          - Psychological Center, New Orleans, La., 1948
          - Psychological testing, 1949
          - Salary Standardization Board, 1948
          - United States Public Health Service, 1945-1950
          - Vision Committee, 1948
          - Yerkes Committee, 1946-1950, (3 folders)
          - Zinser Personnel Service, 1947-1948
      - Fillmore H. Sanford
        - General correspondence, 1950-1956
          - A-B
          - C-Z, (7 folders) (Box 60)
        - Related officers file (Box 61)
          - President, 1951-1954, (5 folders)
          - Recording secretary
            - Agenda and miscellany, 1954
            - Correspondence
              - 1951
              - 1955 (Box 62)
          - Treasurer, 1951-1956, (2 folders)
        - Committees file, 1952-1956, (5 folders)
        - Convention Program Committee file, 1950-1956, (5 folders) (Box 63)
        - Council of Editors file
          - Editor, American Psychologist
            - Correspondence
              - Nov. 1949-Oct. 1952
              - Jan. 1953-Dec. 1954, (8 folders) (Box 64)
              - 1955, (4 folders) (Box 65)
        - Government agencies file
          - Central Intelligence Agency, 1951
          - Civil Defense Administration, 1951
          - Civil Service Commission, 1952
          - Department of State, 1951-1952
          - Department of the Army
            - Adjutant General's Office, 1950
            - Armed Forces Institute, 1951-1952
            - Human Resources Research Office, 1952
            - Miscellaneous, 1953
            - Office of the Surgeon General, 1951-1952
          - Department of the Navy, Office of Naval Research, contracts, 1954 (Box 66)
          - Federal Security Agency
            - Child Bureau, 1951-1953
            - Education Office, 1951-1952
          - Interdepartmental Committee on Scientific Research and Development, 1952
          - Miscellany, 1951
          - National Institute of Mental Health, 1951
          - Office of Defense Mobilization 1951-1952
          - Veterans Administration
            - General, 1952
            - Vocational Rehabilitation and Guidance, 1951
        - Organizations file
          - American Psychological Foundation, 1953
          - American Public Health Association, 1954
          - National Association for Mental Health, Requests regarding clinical psychology, 1950-1951
          - National Research Council
            - Committee on Highway Safety Research, 1951
            - Committee on International Exchange of Persons, 1951-1955
            - Committee on Undersea Warfare, 1950-1951
            - Correspondence, 1950-1956
            - Miscellany, 1953
            - Office of Scientific Personnel, 1950-1951
            - Personnel, 1952
            - Psi Chi, 1951-1956
            - Research and Development Board, 1952
            - Research in psychology, 1945-1953
            - Retirement plans, 1954-1955 (Box 67)
            - Science and Education Project, 1954-1956
            - Second International Gerontological Congress, 1951
            - Thorndike Medal, 1950-1952
            - Veterans Administration report on clinical psychology section, 1951-1952
          - National Society for Medical Research, 1951-1955
        - Representatives file
          - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1950-1956, (2 folders)
          - American Documentation Institute, 1951-1955, (2 folders)
            - American Standards Association, 1950-1958, (2 folders)
          - Council of National Organizations, 1953-1956, (2 folders)
          - Delegates and representatives, 1954-1955
          - Groupement Internationale Pour la Coordination dela Psychiatrie, 1950-1956, (2 folders)
          - International Society of Color Council
            - Correspondence, 1950-1956, (2 folders)
            - Reports and miscellany, 1951-1953 (Box 68)
          - National Conference for Mobilization of Education, 1950-1951
          - National Council on Rehabilitation, 1951
          - National Society for Crippled Children and Adults, 1952-1956
          - Scientific Manpower Commission, 1952-1956, (2 folders)
          - Social Science Research Commission, 1950-1956, (2 folders)
          - United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization, 1951-1956, (2 folders)
          - World Federation for Mental Health, 1950-1956, (2 folders) (Box 69)
        - Subject file
          - Accounts and finances
            - American Security and Trust Co., 1954
            - General correspondence, 1951-1958
            - Taxes, 1955-1956
          - American Men of Science, 1955-1959
          - Armed Forces Familiarization Courses in Military Psychology Lectures, 1950-1951
          - Board of Directors, loyalty investigations, 1951-1952
          - Forensic information, 1952-1955
          - Inauguration, 1954
          - Legal counsel, 1951-1956
          - Library, archives, and museum collection, 1956
          - Syracuse University, Syracuse, N.Y., Report, 1952
      - Roger Russell
        - General correspondence, 1956-1960
          - A-B, (2 folders)
          - C-L, (6 folders) (Box 70)
          - M-Z, (5 folders) (Box 71)
        - Related officers file, recording secretary, 1956
        - Organizations file
          - American Child Guidance Foundation
            - Correspondence and reports, 1956-1958
            - Miscellany, 1956-1958 (Box 72)
          - National Association of Mental Health, 1958-1959
          - National Commission on Accreditation, 1950-1953
          - National Institute of Mental Health, 1959
          - National Society for Medical Research, 1956-1957
        - Representatives file
          - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1956-1957, (2 folders)
          - American Documentation Institute, 1957
          - American Medical Association, 1957, (2 folders)
          - American Standards Association, 1957, 1959
          - Council of National Organizations, 1956-1959
          - Groupement Internationale Pour la Coordination de la Psychiatrie, 1956-1957
          - International Society of Color Council, 1957
          - National Research Council, 1956-1958
          - National Society for Crippled Children and Adults, 1956-1958
          - National Tuberculosis Association, 1959
          - Scientific Manpower Commission, 1956-1958
          - Social Science Research Council, 1956-1957
          - World Federation of Health, 1956-1958 (Box 73)
        - Subject file
          - Accounts and finances, 1958
          - American Teachers' Association, 1948
          - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils International exchange of persons
            - Correspondence, 1956-1958
            - Miscellany, 1959
          - Congressional testimony, 1958
          - Financial support for research in psychology, 1959
          - Forensic information, 1957-1958
          - Joint Commission on Mental Illness and Health, 1957-1959
          - Legal counsel, 1956-1958
          - Mental Health Book Review Index, 1959
          - Mental health testimony, 1952-1957
          - Miscellany, 1958-1959
          - Muller Committee on Support for Behavioral Science, 1958
          - Office of Vocational Rehabilitation, psychosocial study section pamphlets, 1957 (Box 74)
          - Officers of scientific societies, 1958-1959
          - Peace project, undated
          - Project on Scientific Information Exchange in Psychology, 1957
          - Research in education, 1958
          - Science and education project, 1957-1958, (3 folders)
          - Science course improvement project, undated
          - Social science cooperation, 1959
          - Soviet literature, 1958-1959
          - Television project, Jung, 1957-1958 (Box 75)
          - USSR trip, 1958
      - John Gordon Darley
        - Daily directories, 1959-1964, (3 folders)
        - General correspondence
          - May-Sept. 1959, (2 folders)
          - Oct. 1959-Mar. 1960, (6 folders) (Box 76)
          - Apr.-Aug. 1960, (5 folders) (Box 77)
          - Sept. 1960-Jan. 1961, (5 folders) (Box 78)
          - Feb.-July 1961, (6 folders) (Box 79)
          - Aug. 1961-Jan. 1962, (6 folders) (Box 80)
          - Feb.-June 1962, (5 folders) (Box 81)
          - July 1962-June 1964, (4 folders) (Box 82)
        - Representatives file
          - Delegates and representatives, 1960-1962
          - Interprofessional Research Commission on Pupil Personnel Services, 1961-1962, (3 folders)
          - Joint Commission on Mental Illness and Health, 1961-1962 (Box 83)
          - Managing officers of scientific societies, 1959-1962
          - Miscellaneous material, 1962
          - National Association for Mental Health, 1959-1961
          - National Society for Crippled Children and Adults, 1960
        - Miscellany
          - Grants
            - Inquiries, 1959-1962
            - Research, 1959-1961
          - Invitations, 1959-1962
          - Membership, 1959-1961
          - Office administration, 1960-1962
        - Subject file (Box 84)
          - Aging legislation, 1959
          - Air force affairs, 1959
          - American Council on Education, 1959-1960
          - American Men of Science, 1961
          - Arms control/disarmament, 1961-1962
          - Civil service issue, 1959-1960
          - Clinical psychology consultant, Surgeon General, Department of the Army, 1960-1962
          - Council for Research in Education
            - 1959-1961, (2 folders)
            - 1962 (Box 85)
          - Division 12: Clinical Psychology, 1961-1962
          - Fulbright Fellowship, Herbert Kelman Case, 1959
          - Insurance, 1961-1962
          - Jenkins case
            - Court briefs, 1961-1962, (2 folders)
            - Miscellaneous material, 1961-1962
          - Legal counsel, 1962
          - Michigan doctoral program for clinical studies, 1962
          - Office of Vocational Rehabilitation, 1960-1962
          - Peace Corps, 1961 (Box 86)
          - South Africa Psychological Association, undated
          - Television projects
            - Committees, 1961
            - Correspondence, 1960-1962
            - Miscellaneous material, 1960-1962
            - Proposals, 1960-1962
            - Scripts
              - General, 1961-1962, (2 folders)
              - "A Room with a View," 1961
          - USSR
            - Articles, 1960-1962
            - Correspondence, 1960
            - Reports, 1959-1961, (4 folders) (Box 87)
            - Russian literature, 1959
            - Russian Travelers Group, 1960
            - Travel, 1959-1960
          - United States Information Agency, Ralph White matter, 1961-1962
    - Executive officer (Box 88)
      - Arthur H. Brayfield
        - General correspondence
          - Aug. 1962-Dec. 1964, (5 folders)
          - Jan. 1965-May 1966, (5 folders) (Box 89)
          - June 1966-May 1967, (5 folders) (Box 90)
          - June 1967-Oct. 1968, with Acting Executive officer Charles Gersoni, (4 folders) (Box 91)
        - Chronological file
          - Oct.-Dec. 1962, (3 folders)
          - Jan.-Sept. 1963, (9 folders) (Box 92)
          - Oct. 1963-Aug. 1964, (11 folders) (Box 93)
          - Sept. 1964-Dec. 1967, (8 folders) (Box 94)
        - General administrative file (Box 95)
          - Academic freedom, University of Florida, Tallahassee, Fla., 1967
          - Accreditation, undated
          - Administrative organization, 1964-1965
          - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1962
          - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1963
          - American Documentation Institute, 1964
          - American Medical Association and mental health, 1963
          - American Men of Science, 1964
          - American Hospital Association, 1965
          - American Psychiatric Association, 1966
          - American Psychologist
            - Editorial functions, 1965
            - Indices, 1962
          - American Public Health Association, 1965
          - American Speech and Hearing Association, 1964-1965
          - Behavioral sciences, Congressional hearings, 1966-1967
          - Board of Directors, 1962-1966, (3 folders)
          - Board of Professional Affairs
            - General, 1962-1964
            - Insurance Committee, 1965 (Box 96)
            - Policy on community health programs, 1964
          - Building Committee, 1963
          - Business Office
            - Budget, 1963-1964, 1968
            - General, 1962-1963- 1968
          - Chicago conference, Chicago, Ill., 1965
          - Civil rights bill, 1964-1965
          - Clark Committee, 1964-1965
          - Classification conference, 1965
          - Committee on Relations with Local Clinical Groups, 1963-1965
          - Community mental health
            - Background, 1965-1966
            - Medicare, 1966
            - Miscellaneous, 1965 (Box 97)
          - Community mental health centers, 1965-1966
          - Community mental health legislative campaigns, 1964-1965
          - Community mental health programs, 1964-1966, (4 folders)
          - Community on mental health, 1965
          - Complaints, undated
          - Consumer psychologists, 1968
          - Council for research in education, 1963
          - Division 9: Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues, 1962-1964 (Box 98)
          - Division 12: Clinical Psychology
            - Conference
              - Grant continuation, 1964-1965
              - Observers, 1965
            - General, 1963-1965, (3 folders)
            - Reports, 1966-1967
            - Training conference, 1962-1965
          - Division 15: Industrial Psychology, 1962-1964
          - Division 16: School Psychology, 1965-1967 (Box 99)
          - Divisions, 1965-1966
          - Dues, 1964-1965
          - Educational testing, 1962-1965
          - Endorsement requests, 1964
          - Fact Magazine, Barry M. Goldwater matter, 1964
          - Federal legislation, 1963-1965
          - Full Opportunity and Social Accounting Act, 1967
          - Gardner, John, material concerning, 1966
          - Georgia speech, 1965-1966
          - Headquarters building
            - Dedication
              - Arrangements, 1965
              - Brochure, 1965
              - General, 1965, (2 folders)
              - Invitations, 1965
              - Press publicity, 1965
              - Program, 1965
            - Financial plan, 1962
            - Miscellaneous, 1962-1963
            - Nigerians, 1963 (Box 100)
            - Proposals, 1962